mailmunch.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy - MailMunch Legal

MailMunch is a suite of email collection and email marketing solutions (“MailMunch” or “Services”). Your privacy and protection of information you share with us while using our Services is very important to us.

This "Privacy Policy" explains what information we gather from our users and how we use it. By using or accessing our Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. (Capitalized terms not defined herein have the meaning set forth in our Terms of Service). MailMunch is not intended for children under 13 years of age. Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), we will never knowingly gather or use personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13, and we do not allow anyone under the age of 13 to register on MailMunch.

## **What information does MailMunch gather?**

MailMunch gathers and stores three types of information about users that are subject to our Privacy Policy:

**Information users provide to us:**

These are voluntary submissions made when creating an account on MailMunch or through your use of the Services, such as name and email address provided during registration and form submissions, or payment information provided during purchases. Please understand that when you sign into MailMunch or post or upload any content, your information is not anonymous to us.

**Information we collect when users interact with MailMunch:**

We keep track of user interactions with our Services, such as visiting a web page, clicking a button, and choosing a form. Also, when users access our Services, we may collect information about their access method (such as hardware and software attributes), location, IP address, and pages they visit. In addition, we store certain information from their browser using “cookies”. (For more on cookies, please see the section "What are cookies?")

**Information we receive from third parties:**

We do not own or operate any third-party services offered that you may use or interact with through our Services (collectively, “Third Party Services”). Whenever you visit, use or interact with a Third Party Service, we may receive information from them, including information about actions you take and Content you post on that service. Why does MailMunch gather information about me?

## **Why does MailMunch gather information about me?**

MailMunch collects information in order to improve the content and quality of our Services and to provide a customized experience tailored to your needs. Any personally identifiable information we collect (including email addresses, physical addresses or phone numbers) is not shared with or sold to other organizations for commercial purposes, except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission, or under special circumstances outlined in this Privacy Policy.

## **What are cookies?**

MailMunch may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. These cookies help us make MailMunch easier to use, to make our advertising better, and to protect both you and MailMunch. For example, a cookie may be used to store or "remember" your Member login information (but not your password) so that you are not required to manually log into the site at every visit. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases that may impact your ability to use some of our Services.

Notwithstanding any other provision, we partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you or your business. Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer, device, or directly in our emails/communications, and we may share personal information with them if you have submitted such information to us, such as your name, postal address, email address, or device ID. Our partners may link the hashed or obfuscated personal information we share with them to the cookie stored on your browser or device, and they may collect information such as your IP address, browser or operating system type and version, and demographic or inferred-interest information. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms, including but not limited to, computers, mobile devices, and Smart TVs, over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. For example, our partners may deliver an ad to you in your web browser based on a purchase you made in a physical retail store, or they may send a personalized marketing email to you based on the fact that you visited a particular website. Your data may be transferred outside of the country from which it was originally collected. To learn more about interest-based advertising in general and to opt out, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

For more information, please see the section "What about third party advertisers and links?"

## **What about third-party advertisers and links?**

In the course of serving advertisements on MailMunch, a third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Additionally, some links from MailMunch may lead to websites operated by other companies. While these websites and advertisements may be co-branded with our name or logo, they are not operated or maintained by us. We do not control these cookies and users of MailMunch Services should check the privacy policy of the relevant advertiser to understand whether and how it uses cookies. MailMunch is not responsible for websites operated by third parties that are linked to by any of our sites.

Ads appearing on the Services may be delivered to you by Google Ad Manager, DoubleClick, or other advertising partners. Information about your visits to this site, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address or other personal information), is used to serve ads to you. For more information about these partners, their cookies, and how to "opt-out," please follow the links below.

  * Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)
  * Google Ad Manager
  * DoubleClick

## **How secure is my information?**

MailMunch uses commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural measures to safeguard any information in our possession against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. We limit access to personal information about you to employees whom we believe reasonably need that information to provide support, products, or services to you or to fulfill their roles within our organization.

Although we have established and maintain security procedures to protect your personally identifiable information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. You can reduce the risk of unauthorized access to your information by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up-to-date antivirus software.

Please report any security violations to us on this automated form.

As creator of the contact lists and associated email campaigns, you are considered the data controller within the meaning of the GDPR, and MailMunch is acting only as a data processor. In this capacity, you are responsible in particular for:

a) Making all the declarations necessary to the relative data protection authority, b) complying with all current regulations in force, including the data protection laws, c) obtaining the explicit consent of the persons concerned when collecting their personal data, d) ensuring your authority to use the personal data collected in accordance with the defined end purposes and refraining from any unauthorised use.

## **What control do I have over my information?**

As a registered Member, you may modify or update your personal account information at any time by logging into your account. Should you desire to do so, you may also delete and close your MailMunch account at any time by contacting our support team. Note that removed or deleted information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time.

In accordance with the French Data Protection Laws, the European General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR) and California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) you have a right of access, correction and removal of your personal data which you may exercise by sending us a support ticket at <https://www.mailmunch.com/contact>. Your requests will be processed within 14 days. We may require that your request be accompanied by a photocopy of proof of identity or authority.

You are also able at any time to modify personal data by logging in and going to the "Account" section.

MailMunch will not share your personally identifiable information with others except as described herein and in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is reasonably necessary to offer the Services, legally required, or permitted by you. For example, we may provide information to service providers to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business, such as to host the Services at a co-location facility for servers, to send out email updates about the Services, to remove repetitive information from our user lists, to process payments for products or services, or to provide search results or links (including sponsored links). In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time.

Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the MailMunch-specified purposes. We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of MailMunch (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by MailMunch, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the MailMunch Terms of Service or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety or rights of members of the public or users of the Services. MailMunch reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of MailMunch or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.

## **How am I notified of changes to this privacy policy?**

We may change this Privacy Policy pursuant to the procedures outlined in our Terms of Service. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information we have about you and your account. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy we will notify you by publication here.

To submit an inquiry about our Privacy Policy, please contact our [support department](https://www.mailmunch.com/contact).
